I
那是圣诞节前夕
[20th Century Fox Fanfare Playing]
一切都很平静
I
连一点动物声音都没有
Voice, Whispering: Antwone. He's here.
可恶
Woman: That's Antwone.
全部拿走
[Bell Rings, Gunshot]
真丑的小孩
Ohh!
我希望圣诞老人给我两袋鲨鱼酱
[Fall Call Whistle Blows]
什么
Man On PA: First call, first call to colors.
我只要两份干酪汉堡
First call,
两片伯罗尼火腿
[Woman On Intercom Speaking Indistinctly]
你在我家做什么 还敢吃东西
Damn. Berkley!
我是圣诞老人
What?
牛奶和饼干在哪里
You've been in there 1 0 minutes, man.
你滚
Shut up.
我想要大块的汉堡
Yeah, okay. You know...
圣诞快乐
one day, Chief's gonna come in here...
可以看见我又回到了贫民区
and catch you taking them Hollywood showers.
只有在这里的圣诞节前夕
I should snitch on you. Come on, move, man.
会被小偷抢劫
Get out of myway, snitch.
不知道我还能坚持这样下去吗
Oh, come on. Yeah, yeah. Ruff!.
真是难过
Ha ha ha! I got you, man.
醒来 我们刚刚被抢
Sailors: Ooh!
快起来 我知道你听见了
Arf!.
走开
You better quit playing, man.
快爬起来 我得打电话叫警察
[Man On Intercom Speaking Indistinctly]
你说什么
What's cracking, Fisher?
我们被抢了
Your head, ifyou don't get away from me.
因为我接受过特别训练
Heh. What is that on your face?
狠踢他几下
Keep the fuck out my face, huh?
去查房间 当然
Say something!
你还遭遇到什么
Say something, huh? You're always talking!
他拿走所有礼物
I'm cool, man, I'm cool.
所有音乐碟
I'm cool. I'm cool, man.
还有小孩照片
Captain: Petty Officer Fisher, you've been accused...
他也拿走喇叭
ofviolating Article 1 28--
里面装了我们的房租钱
Assault on a superior non-commissioned officer.
坐下
How do you plead?
谁拿了我的钱
Guilty, sir.
你现在急什么
Well, in your statement, you sayyour attack...
他快打死我的时候你在哪里
on Petty Officer Berkley was provoked by a...
我需要那笔钱
a racial slur. Is that correct?
很好 现在你没钱交房租了
Yes, sir.
你确定他打扮成圣诞老人?
Petty Officer Berkley, did you make...
白胡须 穿红衣
any racial remarks to Petty Officer Fisher?
带几个小矮人?
No, sir.
他是故意装扮成圣诞老人
Punk, you--
外边穿圣诞老人的衣服
Stand at attention!
里面却是污秽的
Stand at attention.
你能想象的到吗
This is the United States Navy, son.
你知道污秽的人是怎样
I find you guilty.
你应该紧张的 你是警察
They'll be a forfeiture of $200 for 2 months.
你们去搞吧
You'll be restricted to the boundaries ofthe ship...
我哪也不去
for 45 days, and you'll perform 45 days extra duty.
冷静吧
I'm reducing you from ship's serviceman...
我是很冷静
petty officer third class...
回去车上
to ship's serviceman seaman.
你做你的事就行
And I'm recommending thatyou be evaluated...
你别弄错
at the psychiatric clinic...
我们是受害者
before our next underway period. You're dismissed.
说是受害者也太夸张
So, what happened?
你们坐着闭嘴
How'd it go?
又是被圣诞老人抢劫的案件
Same old, same old. I got busted...
让我想回家把东西都锁上
but now I gotta go to the psych clinic.
你最好别这样对我说话
You gotta go to the nut house?
你早上的表现
Farmer, shut up, man.
我应该踢你的
Give it up to the shrink? Damn.
我们还会有圣诞节舞会吗
See you next week.
公寓变成这样
Seaman Fisher.
我们怎么能开舞会
Right this way.
我们怎么办圣诞舞会
I understand it's not your first time here.
可以不要有圣诞舞会
You saw Dr. Williams?
可是我得给女朋友买礼物
Nah, he saw me.
我知道她们会喜欢我
Heh.
我不能让自己这样悲惨
That's yourwife?
我不在乎你,也不在乎舞会
Yes.
我只担心房租
Have a seat.
是你的主意吧...
I understand you like to fight.
我想这里有东西
It's the onlyway some people learn.
那是我们两个的
Hmm. Butyou pay the price for teaching them.
不是
You want to talk about it?
是的 它是为需要而准备的
About what?
他有白内障
Whatever's bothering you.
看见吗
Why does something gotta be bothering me?
你们知道我们能怎样处治你们吗
What, because I jumped on a white boy?
不知道 少年拘留所?
Something must be wrong with me?
我们可以让你们更可怜
"Send him to the psychiatrist.
因为是星期五
Nigger try to kill his master."
你们星期一才能见法官
Hmph.
因为我们是好人
"He must be crazy."
我们只要没收这棵植物
You looking for a discharge, Fisher?
直到找到圣诞老人
I ain't looking for nothing.
太惨了
That's where you're headed.
等我们找到圣诞老人尼克
Ifl want out ofthe navy...
你们要我们怎么对他?
I'll just leave.
打破头...
Unauthorized absence?
打破头
Yeah, ifthat's what the navy calls it.
我会去的
Hmm. Running away howyou handleyour problems?
我说你用植物打他吧
I don't have no problems.
这是迪克警官
Hmm. Whereyou from, Fisher?
我是贺尔警官
Where'd you spend your childhood?
有消息我们就通知你们
Cleveland.
A 贺尔警官 B 迪克警官
Parents still live there?
我们会找你们
I never had any parents.
他们真好
They deceased?
对了 你们床边有一堆狗屎
I never--
最好去看一看
I never had parents.
这里发生什么事
That would make you...
节日快乐 伯里太太
a medical miracle, Seaman Fisher.
你们到处吵
Where you from?
到底发生什么
I'm from under a rock.
今天早上有人闯进我们的公寓
Okay.
偷走全部的东西
Okay, all right.
希望他们没偷你们的房租钱
I want to see you next week.
你们俩欠我的房租已拖了3星期
I ain't coming back.
今天是你们最后一天交钱
Why not?
你为何总是来骚扰我们
'Cause there's nothing wrong with me.
你又不是房东
I agree with you there.
你只是个经理
See you next week.
如果再不交房租
See the receptionist on yourway out.
我就把你们驱逐出去
Next Wednesday, 1 400.
你们别担心 我知道你们这种人
Whoa!
你最好回楼下
Walker. Phillip Walker.
你谁也不能驱逐
That was the name of the last guywho stalked me.
你连军队都没有
Oh, man, I'm busted.
我不需要军队
Yeah, you're busted.
我儿子是戴蒙
What's up? Whereyou been?
戴蒙
I'm on restriction.
昨晚我做恶梦 梦见了他
- Again? - Yeah.
今晚你们谁想洗我的衣服
How did you get off the ship?
他
Um, well, I just came from the medic.
我本来就要洗的
Why?
开始吧 黑鬼
Uh, well...
走开
I'm working on this high priority paper...
别这样 太太
for this commander.
他何时出狱
Oh. What kind of paper?
昨晚
Well, I'm-- I'm not at liberty...
我要告诉你们俩一个秘密
to talk about it right now.
当你坐牢12年
Oh. Well, I was gonna inviteyou to a party.
你会喜欢象你们这样的女孩
Me?
如果我没拿到房租
Yeah, you.
有人要被驱逐了
Well, I'm on restriction.
你知道这个没有必要
Yeah, you told me.
我和大卫今天就开始工作
Hmm. I gotta...
我发誓
you know, get back to the ship.
晚上以前我们会把现金拿到你手上
They probably looking for me...
你们最好这样
right about now, so...you know--
你们若没来找我
Talk to you.
戴蒙就会去找你们
[Whispering] Damn.
就这么简单
See you when you're off restriction.
你喜欢你儿子回来吗
[Telephone Rings]
闭嘴
I
告诉你的父亲我说...
Yes?
真讨厌那家伙
Yeah, send him in.
什么裤子嘛
Get your monkey hands off me, man!
穿这种裤子
I thought you may have forgotten...
就不能象布朗那样做了
yourway here last week, so I took the liberty...
穿这种衣服永远不能吸引女孩
of sending an escort team foryou.
我们好看吗
You may be able to make me come here...
好象工人
but you can't make me talk.
看见吗 衣服能改变人
Thankyou. You're dismissed.
我是保安 不是工人
You don't want to talk to me?
克雷格和大卫
Let me lay this out foryou, son.
正是我要找的黑人
This is how many cases I have, okay?
你好吗 OGOG
I don't have time to waste.
你昨晚出狱吗
Now, I get 3 sessions only...
我12年没见你们
to make an eval...
给我一个拥抱
and a recommendation to your commanding officer.
我要跑了
You know he wants to throw you...
过来
out of the navy, don't you?
还有你
Now, you can sit here, and you can not talk...
快点 克雷格
to me ifyou want to...
我知道
but our sessions don't begin...
我们得彼此帮助
until you begin talking to me.
是的
I got nothing to say.
听说你们不付房租
Okay.
今晚若不交房租
Then we'll sit until you do.
我们就有好看
I got a whole lot of work to catch up on.
我们会有房租
We can sit here every day...
他不能呼吸
until the day I retire. Doesn't matter to me.
别让我失望
It doesn't matter to me, either.
很好
- All righty. - What about the brig?
因为我只说一次
What about it?
走吧
Send me to the brig.
你们很好啊
There's the brig right there.
圣诞快乐
Lockyourself up.
可恶 他会给我们好看的
What do you know? Time's up.
我完了
See you next week, 1 400.
可恶
Want some chips?
大约一年前
Hmph.
我爸爸跟叔叔一起合作
[Clears Throat]
他们经营一家烤肉店
[Coughing]
味道很棒
What?
让你吃不停
I didn't say anything.
你们想吃好吃的烧烤
I thought you said something.
那就来兄弟烧烤店
Ahem. I was just clearing my throat.
在曼切斯特街附近
Okay.
味道很好 让你吃不停
[Clears Throat]
妈
Maybe you're coming down with something.
做什么
Ahem. I'm all right.
我们只有足够钱买一点东西
[Wheezes]
爸给我们工作做
It's just sort of...
圣诞节能增加保安的工作
Just what?
我们只是保安
Just...
白天在贫民区当保安
It's just a waste oftime sitting here...
我们不是警察
week afterweek...
也不是国家要抓的人
wasting time.
或是纽约警察
I don't want you...
我们是其中一个
to waste your time, Antwone.
不 不是
So, whatyou want me to say?
所以我们得放松
It's not what I want you to say.
赚老实钱
It's what you want to tell me.
你得赚房租的钱
Maybe you can start by asking me a question.
要好好待人
I don't know. Get things going.
才不会很快就被人开除
I can do that.
我不要因为你的缘故而失败
You said you come from under a rock.
这只是工作 不是探险
What did you mean by that?
我要告诉你我并不快乐
I don't know, I...
大家都是嫌疑犯
It was the first thing to come to my mind.
我要继续玩我的
[Sighs]
玩吧
What do you think it means?
你真平庸
Well, it could mean...
那是什么意思
that, uh...
就是有智能障碍
thatyou feel under pressure...
过来看
that, uh...
就是他
uh, you feel a weight...
叔叔
pressing down on you.
你们在对我做什么
That you're in the dark, that you're alone.
我不知道是你
You said you had no parents.
还以为你是别人
I had parents.
你在后面做什么
Okay.
没做什么 只是在算帐
Ahem. Only 3 sessions, right?
这些傻瓜却这样对我
Only 3.
我们出错了 都是他
My father's name was Edward.
你们为何打圣诞老人
So you knew him?
他做了 什么
No.
他抢我的家 偷走我们的礼物
I didn't even know his last name.
都是克雷格
You know where he is?
为什么 克雷格
Yeah, I know where he is.
我喊着他 他却不听
Joey--
他在说谎
He went to his ex-girlfriend's house.
你做了什么
They got into an argument.
他什么也没做
She killed my father.
能说句话吗 爸爸
Where was your mother when this happened?
他必须想办法
Behind bars.
他是什么样子
I see.
他象穿圣诞老人衣服的怪人
I was born in prison...
我也听说过
2 months after my fatherwas murdered.
他们说他是圣诞怪人
Whywas she confined, your mother?
上星期他在停车场抢了一个女士
I don't know.
他叫了:呵呵呵 然后就跑走
All I know is what I told you.
你是谁
So you were turned over to the state?
我是饼干 新来的服务员
Yeah. The state placed me in this orphanage.
艾罗的新女友
It was supposed to be until...
你又找到一个
my mother got out to claim me, but--
去年你应该找甜心的
She got out, but she never claimed me.
她到哪里了
Hmm. How long wereyou there?
我不找那个乡下人了
2 years.
不是这样做的
How does that make you feel, Antwone?
你不是玩手
I don't know.
你不懂什么是玩手
Come on, you must have some feelings about it.
30年来你从没变
You know, you-- What did it feel like?
我不玩完美先生
Rainy days.
你们俩很好嘛
Rainy days? Okay.
你们衣服真好看
Why is that?
爸 看
You know, in Cleveland...
好象有毛病
it rains. Not all the time...
好象你们现在就要抓人
but, uh, to a kid...
有没有手电筒照别人?
who wants to go out and play...
我们有手铐 手电筒
it seems like it rains every day.
上次那位保安怎么了?
But, uh...
艾罗 妈妈在厨房做酱
kids expect it to rain sometimes...
快去
but...for one kid...
以前的保安怎么了
it rained too much.
你要做什么
Hmm.
汤匙在哪里 妈
Okay.
别碰她
You want me to come back next week?
她怎么了
Yes, I do.
你伤他的头 那应该只是演戏
You ever try to find her, your mother?
她好吗
No, sir.
妈 你没事吧
Okay. Next week.
你是谁
Busy day?
我是克雷格
Uh, no more than usual.
谁是克雷格? 别担心
Hmm.
你聪明的长孙
The tomatoes are from our garden.
走开
Yeah?
你加的调味够了
Mmm. They're so much better than last year.
我知道自己在做什么
Heh heh.
你们总是吵架 为什么
I mean, I'm no green thumb or anything...
你们快结婚了
but...heh heh.
你为何总是跟我争
Who knows? Maybe I'm learning.
你在嫉妒
These tomatoes really are good.
没有办法 我比你好
Reverend Tate: & I don't know psychology &
没有
& I don't know zoology, ha &
我比你大
& But I know this, ahh &
才没有
&Jesus &
去年我几乎赢上百万的乐透奖
&Jesus, ha &
你最好给我做烧烤
I
爸和叔叔吵架15分钟后
&Jesus &
我们就见到我们的新老板
Antwone, Voice-over: When I was 2...
他拥有整个购物中心
I was placed in the Tate foster home.
还有甜圈店
Reverend Tate, he was a fire-breathing preacher.
可是最好永远不要去那里吃
He had his own storefront church.
我们要平时吃的
There was only a few members.
莫里
There was Ms. Tate, cousin Nadine...
你好吗
my foster brothers Keith--
圣诞节快乐
Keith was halfwhite--
这些是我孩子
Dwight, and me.
我马上就来
& Good God, yeah &
怎样 生意如何
It was church 3 times on Sunday...
一切都很好
Bible study on Tuesday...
看见我的广告吗
Y.P.W.W. meetings on Thursday...
没有
choir rehearsal on Friday.
烤肉很好让你想打人
We found out ifwe caught the Holy Ghost...
你有什么问题
in front of Ms. Tate...
对不起 只是反射
she'd give us vanilla wafers after church.
各位 你们在找工作吗
So we'd catch it every Sunday.
我要问个问题
& Hallelujah &
什么时候我们才拿到枪
& Hallelujah, hallelujah &
你们是一流的没有武装的保安
& Good God &
还有手电筒
& Come on, church &
女孩如果在垃圾桶后面叫
& Show me &
我就能拿手电筒来帮她
Reverend Tate...
你们是很强壮的人
he didn't like Dwight at all.
不需要这些玩意
He said he had too much pride.
你们只需要这个
So he tried to beat it out ofhim.
有问题就吹口哨
Sometimes, he would even try to beat him to death.
可恶 克雷格
Did he beatyou?
这是很好的圣诞节
No, sir. I think he pitied me.
准备去看一看这里的场地吗
And I liked him for it...
给我一个甜圈
but I was ashamed ofhim.
走了
What about Mrs. Tate?
我们很快就看完
What about her?
你们知道这是我的店
I don't know which one ofyou no-good rotten...
贺里莫利甜圈店
I tookyou in...
很好 你可以得到免费午饭
when your no-account mammies threwyou away...
走
and this is the thanks I get?
这边是商店
Tsk.
这边是你家的烧烤
You ungrateful niggers.
这是兑换现金的地方
[Boys Whimpering]
这是新开的
[Wailing]
叫皮和贺
Hmph. Now I know I got the right one.
我也不知道是什么
Antwone, Voice-over: She used to brag about...
她是谁
beating me unconscious.
那是多娜 是老板的女友
Hmph.
他很有趣
She'd threaten to do it again.
如果有这样的太太就好了
But she never did.
你有几个太太
Why do you think she never did?
我? 12个
Uh...maybe she was scared.
对 全部是怪人
She found a new way to get me, though.
你知道的 朋友
[Young Antwone Panting]
他样子很好笑
So you like fire, huh?
不知道为什么这样打扮
No, Muh-deah, no, Muh-deah...
你好吗? 无所谓
I don't like fire.
拿出去吧
You...
嘿 朋友
stay...
好 这边是酒店
away from things that don't belong to you.
酒店前面不能有人
You hear me?
不能有人
You hear me?!
然后这个是你们的地方
Yes, yes, Muh-deah!
什么
Yes!
以前这里的保安怎么了?
Dumb nigger.
你问的太多 应该去工作了
[Door Creaks Shut]
要记得你们是世界一流的保安
Antwone: I tried everything I could...
你们得用性命保护这个地方
to get her to like me...
记住
and nothing everworked.
圣诞季节会有很多生意
Were you the youngest ofthe foster children?
若有任何问题
No, Dwight was the youngest.
等你们处理后就来找我
I was in the middle, and Keith was the oldest.
去吧
Ms. Tate, she used to put us against each other...
领薪水时你要怎么做
so much, we started hating each other.
别担心那个
But I think deep down inside...
你不要多嘴
we really hated ourselves.
记得戴蒙说的话
What do you mean?
你要记住我的话
Keith was halfwhite.
别想跟我比 你会伤害到自己
She would try to compare Keith...
你要去哪里
to me and Dwight.
这里很小
You know, he had the good hair...
你太大了
and we had the bad hair.
别踏我的脚
She used to say how Keith was better than us...
你过去
because his father was white.
这里很不舒服 连动都不行
I wished I was Keith.
你会习惯
Mmhh.
现在做什么
But not even Keith could escape...
坐着等事情发生
from being called a nigger.
我才不要 很无聊
She hardly used our names.
很好 我喜欢无聊
She said the word nigger so often...
让我们赚钱容易
called us niggers so often...
希望整天都不要出事
that we could tell...
就这样看着女士逛街
who she was talking to by...
注意
the way she said the word nigger.
你听见那先生说的
What happened to Dwight and Keith?
我们是世界一流的保安
Dwight is in Lucasville State Penitentiary.
他们被圣诞老人抢劫
Keith got taken back by his mother.
他们需要安全
He was raped by one ofher boyfriends.
冷静 别急
Mmhh.
别让那人刺激你
Did what happen to Keith happen to you?
我们不是什么一流保安
Hell, no.
放松吧
Okay.
以前的保安怎么了?
Okay. Was Mrs. Tate ever--
连你都不知道 我怎么知道?
Was she ever nice to you?
做你的工作 我也一样
Yeah, there were times.
我会工作的
Sometimes she would tell her friends that...
有行动了
we were good kids and that she was proud of us.
停
Chummy times.
停止这样子
Chummy times?
你们得离开这个角落
Yeah. I got to where I could tell...
对不起 你说什么
what kind of day it was gonna be...
你听见了 快走开
by the scent in the air when I awoke.
你最好注意你的嘴
How could you tell?
你在跟主的孩子说话
Well, ifl awoke and there was the smell...
对
of grits and eggs...
你们也在跟他们说话
orwater steaming off the pavement...
一流的保安
as she hosed it down...
你不能这样跟她们说话
I had to look out all day.
你做你的工作支持我
But...ifl smelled pancakes...
你们走吧
everything was okay.
别推我 也别碰我
She make pancakes very often?
若让我吹口哨
No, sir.
大家都会离开
I can delay my next appointment...
他们应该去教堂
ifyou want to talk some more.
我们要为他们祈祷
No, sir.
你怎么了
Hey, Slim.
不能那样对人说话
What?
我想怎样说就怎样说
You going home next leave?
我是这里的主人
Hell, yeah. I gotta tend to the flock.
让我做我的工作 你做你的
Hey, when I get leave...
我不能相信大卫的行为
I'm gonna be like a--a vampire...
自从有了 口哨
coming to town with his coffin.
他的行为就很差
Just a place to lay before I get down.
不能在这里停车
What's that mean?
为什么
Man, shut up. People trying to sleep.
这里有新的规则
Aw, shut your grouchy ass up.Jesus!
把号码给我
Hey, when you going home, Pork Chop?
不然就不能在这里停车
When your mama quit tripping...
我没听过这样的规则
and send me my money. Ha ha ha!
因为你没见过一流的保安
What aboutyou, Fish?
看这个傻瓜
When you going home?
我结婚了 才没有这种道理
Fish?
再见
Fish!
我做了什么
Antwone, Voice-over: Last night...
为什么滥用你的权威
I had a dream aboutJesse.
你的做人需要改善
Davenport, Voice-over: Who's Jesse?
我的做人技巧比你好多了
He was my best friend.
坐下 放松
When I wasn't at home...
有了
I was probablywherever Jesse was for 3 reasons.
别吹口哨
One was, being his friend...
你怎么了 你不是纽约警察
he wouldn't beat me up.
知道吗
Hey,Jesse, look! I got 5!
不要憎恨 要感谢
And the other reasons were-- so he wouldn't beat me up.
你只是嫉妒我这样做
I only got 3.
别让我安静
I liked him a whole lot.
我没有值班
Give meyours.
我是一流的保安
We used to drive our friend Kenny crazy.
你得知道警察跟保安的区别
Let's get Kenny.
我们不再是小人物
Kenny hung around me...
知道吗
for the same reasons I hung around Jesse.
40岁时你不能再这样玩
Hey, Kenny, let me see.
这个有一天会停
Where's Jesse?
但不是今天 所以你轻松吧
Ugh!
我一直想
Aah! Stop, stop! Get 'em off, get 'em off!.
你对我的影响不好
Hey, Kenny, what's wrong?
自从跟你一起
don't forget to write!
我的生活都很差
Hey, Kenny,
把它给我
Ms. Tate, she hated Jesse.
我才没有坏影响
She hated seeing us together even more.
我是你最好的表兄
But foryears, she couldn't keep us apart.
若不是我你就被欺负
I was so happy when she kicked me out.
我保护了你
Mrs. Tate: Twonny.
你很胆小
That hoodlum niggerJesse call up here askin' foryou.
看
I
只是我们
Said something abouty'all going to the picture show.
你几乎让我心脏发作
Now, that's the devil's work...
我可能伤害你的脑
and who told you you could go...
给我那个
to the picture show, anyhow?
这样的行为能让你坐牢
I mean, where you get the money, nigger?
今天如何?
Did you steal it?
很无聊很安静
I already told you. I've been raking lawns.
等一下吧
Well, you woulda stole it.
无赖到一点之前不会出来
Give me the money.
他们会来
I said gimme the money.
希望来的时候我在这里
You don't know what to do with no money nohow.
转过去
That's why I never let you have none.
转过去 你有什么东西
Whyyou always got to make things...
我什么没有
difficult for me?
你看什么
Difficult?
我是不是认识你
Difficult.
你有什么东西
Where you learnin' such fancywords at?
你提醒我
Fancy? Ain't no fancyword.
一个小黑人找错了 大黑人
Don't sassy me, boy.
手表给我
No one's sassing you.
不能给你劳力克
Don't sassy me!
他拿我的劳力克
Ain't no one sassing you!
你们没听见我吹口哨?
Don't you--
什么事
I ain't gonna let you beat me no more!
圣诞老人抢我们
No more!
不管了
Lord Jesus.
别碰我
I want you out of my house.
爸和表兄刚刚被圣诞老人抢劫
Hmm?
你不是保安吗
And whoyou think gonna takeyou in, huh?
所以我向你要两个手电筒
Retarded nigger, don't nobodywantyou.
我讨厌那个停车场
Your damn mammy didn't even wantyou.
给我手电筒 不然我们会死
Mrs. Tate: Gimme my shoe. Hmpf!.
想抓人就该抓拿走我手表的人
Davenport: Must've felt pretty good...
什么保安嘛
when you took that shoe from her.
你去哪 妈
Yeah, I felt like I was gonna go...
我要买早饭
right upside her head...
回来能给我做三明治吗
but I just chilled.
自己做三明治吧
Why'd you chill?
有人在家吗
I don't know.
什么 信笺怎么了
Well, I'm glad you did.
这里很脏
How'd you feel?
给我这些药
I felt like I won a prize...
我不想谈了
but it scared me.
你们只要抓人就行
Why?
你回去做什么
It was the first time I ever felt...
我去拿垃圾
more powerful than her.
如果你把生意弄坏
It was like a surprise.
注意我给你好看
Whatever happened to Jesse?
等等 这个生意是我开始的
We lost touch. You know how it is.
感谢你信任我
Davenport: Yeah.
你们第二次被圣诞节老人抢劫?
It might be helpful to understand the mentality...
是
of people like the Tates.
这是黑人
Here.
有机会再来
It's called The Slave Community.
所有都是7.5折
Why I gotta understand somebody beatin' on me?
爸 他也吹口哨
What you went through...
克雷格
was in part the result of the treatment...
你注意点
that slaves received from their masters...
不知道在80度温度
and then passed on to their own children...
能做出雪人
generation to generation to generation...
有一瓶雪什么都可能
right on down to the Tates.
我是克雷格
Sir, that sounds like an excuse.
我是多娜
I mean, I was a kid.
你们卖什么
I understand.
什么都有
You sound like you takin' up for 'em.
你想找什么
I'm not saying what they did was right.
不知道 什么都比这个好
What they did was wrong.
你很会开玩笑
We all have choices. They made the wrong choices.
你可以给女朋友买东西
But this is not about them. This is aboutyou.
我通常在这时候离开女朋友
You were sent to me...
就不用买东西给她们
because you have an anger problem.
真的
Well, you got the right to be angry.
是
But you also have to learn to channel that anger...
我只是开玩笑
to use it constructively.
那是你朋友
Instead of gettin' into fights...
宝贝 你好吗
go to the gym.
我叫大卫
Hit the bag, lift the weights.
这是我表兄
You have to use that energy to betteryourself.
我刚刚看见你
You sayyou're taking Japanese classes, right?
你要知道你很美丽
Yeah.
如果有麻烦就告诉我
Okay, you're already on the right track.
我给你联络号码
Can we talk about this next week?
我们回去了
3 sessions, son. Unfortunately...
可是她喜欢我
that's all I'm given to make a recommendation...
快点
and I'm gonna recommend...
我想知道她是否看见圣诞节老人
thatyou be given a second chance.
你在这里做什么
That is whatyou want, isn't it?
对不起 我得帮他
To stay in the navy?
她喜欢我
Yes, sir.
没有
Okay. Okay, stay out oftrouble.
她喜欢我 怎么会喜欢你?
Cheryl: Antwone!
能帮你吗
Antwone!
我需要帮助
What's up? How you doing?
我喜欢这个 尺寸是多少?
I'm cool.
你还好吗
Oh. You don't seem cool.
我很好
I'm all right.
看见吗
What are you doin' in there?
走
You still workin' on that paper?
你们要坐牢
No, I'm finished.
为什么
I just went through there for a short cut.
因为偷东西
Oh. Whereyou goin'?
你要坐牢
Nowhere.
我不相信你这样做
I--I gotta go.
你们去了吧
Cheryl, I'll talk toyou later.
艾罗在哪里
[Laughing Together]
在后面 马上就回来
Whyyou always talkin' about somebody's momma?
我们必须打架
Man, we ain't talkin' about somebody's momma.
过来
We talkin' aboutyour momma!
艾罗 你样子很可爱
Hey, Fish!
这是白人的节日
Yeah, I bet you won't be fightin'
这里有孩子 你有什么问题
no more honkies on this boat.
现在不是复活节
Man, this ain't no boat.
今天是圣诞节前夕
Dis a ship.
希望你节日愉快
"Dis a ship!"
节日愉快 回去吧
Country-ass Negro, who letyou in the navy?
布莱
Fish!
不 放他走
What's that book you readin'?
不
Let me see the cover.
给我
The Slave Community.
想想你母亲
Whatcha readin' that shit for?
和你母亲说的话
Because I want to.
怎样
This ain't no slave ship.
这是我女朋友多娜
And these ain't no slavery days.
你好
I can't tell.
我们刚刚开业
You the only buck-dancin' Uncle Tom on the ship.
有一些问题
You a part-time brother.
很感激你们帮忙
Yo, Grayson, man, what--
抓到这些贼都是你们的功劳
Whyyou always talkin' shit, man?
他们偷东西时
What I do ain't got nothing to do with you.
你没注意到?
You better get out of my face, bro.
我没看见他们偷东西
Eitheryou tryin' to hang out with the brothers...
下次要用眼睛看
oryou tryin' to hang with the white boys, man.
这个不是好玩的
You better sit your ass back--
对不起
You better make up your mind. What you gonna do?
不要说对不起
Whatcha gonna do? Come on!
我厌烦你了
Stop it!
可以回去
Let me go! Get your hands--
很高兴见到你们
[Laughing]
我得确保这里安全
Thankyou, sir.
感谢你们的帮忙
Who's next?
不用交钱
So, um, Dr. Davenport...
我们的房租呢
Hit the punchin' bags?
这是我们的工作
Ain't that what you prescribin'?
好 不跟你们争辩
So, why areyou here?
我们能得到7折的衣服吗
You feelin' under pressure?
你不需要那些东西
You feel like, uh, a rock is on top ofyou?
晚上我们有圣诞节舞会
Come on now. Speak the hell up.
你和女朋友可以来
You better make it snappy.
让我看看
You only got 3 sessions comin'!
我有空啊
What are y'all lookin' at?
我会去的 以后再见
What you lookin' at?!
等一等
You feelin' sick?
我需要的时候再让我知道
You need a healin'?
我喜欢他 真的
Doyou need a healin', huh? Doyou need a healin'?!
算了
Some ofy'all sick-ass sailors...
圣诞节你想要什么
need to come back afterworking hours!
我要很多车子
See, that's when the good Dr. Davenport...
这是我的地址 琼斯先生
he'll be layin' his hands on you!
他是圣诞节老人
Or he may have a book in there...
才怪 你是琼斯先生
that may have the answers to all your problems...
我也知道你的住处
and all your questions! Ain't that right?!
他不象鹿 他象水牛
Ain't that right?
别胡来 不然就咬你
Would you like to step into my office?
想看吗
[Door Slams]
我什么都没拿
Areyou finished?
让我走
I thought I was just gettin' started.
保重
Let me tell you something, son.
好吗
It may have slipped your mind...
半小时见你们
butyou are addressing a superior officer.
别迟到
You understand me?
我们没有未来的
Do you understand me?!
走吧
Yes, sir. I slipped up.
抓住他们
You better believe you did.
今天很多工作
No, sir, I mean I slipped up...
能帮你吗
when I talked to you.
不用
What?
不用?
3 sessions, right?
这里真是可怕
That's correct.
多娜
Can't be floutin' regulations.
11点半我要出去
That's correct.
能帮你吗
Well, what do I do, Commander?
走开
'Cause I don't know what to do.
你以为自己是谁
I don't know
你不能到后面
Tired?
快
[Chuckles]
走
How was your day?
你在干什么
Long.
快点
Not complaining, though.
听说你们新来的保安在这里
Well, don't wait up.
如果看见他们
I got a lot ofwork to do.
就说这是我们要说的
I know.
救命
- Good night.
抓到我们后他们会踢我们
Well, it's nice to finally be off...
他们不能抓到我们
restriction for a change.
走吧
Yeah, I'm gonna be squared away from now on.
看什么
Hey!
跳下去
Y'all need somethin' from the exchange?
不能再这样工作下去
Man, what's up with you and the exchange?
快叫警察
You spend more time there than you do on restriction.
你怎么回来
I'm just tryin' to be a good shipmate, man.
你好吗
I'm only kiddin' with you.
现在是我们的午饭休息时间
But bring me back some Skittles.
很好
And a Snickers.
你们在吃饭 而我正被挨打
And some pork skins.
你们应该是保安
And a sandwich. Thankyou.
我们是保安
What areyou doin' here, sir?
不是 你们都被开除
I was in the area and sawyour ship.
不能
Soyou just saw this big ol' ship...
我们才得到这个工作
moored alongside the pier?
怎能开除我们
I want to seeyou back in my office...
把口哨给他
next Wednesday, after knockoff.
出去
That is, ifyou want to continue.
你要怎么做
I think I need to check my calender first...
我知道 你们留在这里
sir.
救命 快来救命
Okay.
克雷格 晚上你开舞会?
Well, you let me know, okay?
不知道
Yes, sir.
我已经没心情了
I
不能没心情 这是圣诞节
Hey, Cheryl.
你要怎么办
- Hey.
大家正担心得到什么礼物
What's going on?
大卫和我却担心别的
Nothing.
这时我想到一个主意
You just gettin' offwork?
我们让人们付钱来踢我们
Yeah.
你要加什么
Oh.
圣诞节快乐
You, uh-- You mad?
我很开心
I'm sorry.
店里的事很好
That's cool. [Chuckles]
每次看见你都很开心
So, you finally off restriction?
既然你口袋有钱
Yeah. [Chuckles]
晚上我们有踢舞会
So you can hang out now?
过来看
Yeah.
女士
So what about now? I'm off.
过来对克雷格打招呼
Nah, I gotta-- I gotta meet somebody.
这是我的热门女孩
Well, I promised I'd meet somebody...
更好的拉拉
in a few minutes, so...you know.
嘿
What's her name?
瑟达
[Chuckles] Look, it ain't like that.
你好吗
It ain't like that.
你样子真好
What about tomorrow?
圣诞节快乐
Um, what about the day after tomorrow?
喜欢吃吗
Say, Wednesday, after knockoff?
你好吗
That'd be better.
一切都好吗
Okay. Um...
很好
meet me in the lobby of the female barracks...
放松 这些都是我的人
at 1 700.
还有靴子女郎
Okay. All right.
那是谁
I'll meet you at 1 700.
她是多娜
All right. Yeah.
她样子真好
It's a date.
谢谢你来 真的
Antwone: Are we done?
没问题 谢谢你的邀请
Davenport: Yes, we are.
介绍你的朋友给我 克雷格
Can I askyou a question?
这是迈克
Sure.
这是多娜
Um... do you think it's--
圣诞节快乐
Do you think it's possible...
可以给我一杯饮料吗
for somebody that had problems all their life...
在哪里?
you know, not to stay that way?
你坐牢过吗
You know, you think it's possible...
没有
they can change?
克雷格
Absolutely. Why do you ask?
是
No reason.
厕所在哪
Do you want something to drink?
我得赶快去小解
- No, I'm good, sir. - Okay.
怎样 看什么
Uh, you know, you--
我不喜欢这个
You know, when you kinda meet somebody...
请排队
you know, ifyou have problems...
现在很忙
it wouldn't--
别抵抗
Who is she? What's her name?
你做什么
Cheryl.
这是我的名片 可以联系
She works at the exchange.
我在烧烤店工作 可以来光顾
That's a good thing. Keep it navy.
混蛋
[Chuckles] Right?
他去了很久
So?
我说过他不舒服 可能在吐
Um... so, um...
你在这里等一下
Have you spoken to heryet?
好
Yeah, I spoke to her, but, um...
房间很干净嘛
I get caught up-- tongue-tied.
这是很好的床
Everybody's awkward at first.
你很好笑
Okay.
只想接近你
No, not like me.
为什么来加州?
No, everybody is, Antwone. Trust me.
我也问自己同样问题
Even you?
为什么要离开家人来这里
Even me. Everybody.
他把你带到这里
So...
然后对你这样差?
Well, we're going out tonight.
不要这样
Good.
你有套子吗
We supposed to go out a couple of days ago...
大卫 你出去
but, uh, you know...
出去
I just wanted to clear my head.
别注意他
Take some time.
迈克回来之前我们走吧
You know, talk to you first.
给你一个建议
Okay. Yeah.
这个门要装锁
So, what should I do?
好吧
[Laughs] Well, she's a nice girl?
出来
Yeah, obviously you like her.
谁在厕所
Mm-hmm.
快点出来
Okay, I thinkyou should just go out with her.
你可以到楼下经理那里去
I mean...
好了
I tell you what. You know, sometimes it helps...
我是克雷格的父亲
just to take the anxiety out of a future meeting...
我们在楼上有舞会
to role play.
厕所里有人
What's that?
你很好看
Like, you playyourself and I'll play Cheryl...
介意我用你的厕所吗
and I'll askyou some questions...
不 进来吧
and we'll have a conversation...
在哪里
and you'll see that you'll have a good time, okay?
走廊那边
Yeah, you play Cheryl.
我需要的就是这个
Okay, now. That's right.
你在跟谁跳舞
I'm man enough to play Cheryl.
别担心
Okay. Uh, you go first.
别碰我
Nah.
你洒水
I'll go first.
醒来
So...
我还以为在做梦
how you doing?
这不是梦
Fine.
你疯了吗
Good, good.
想求我吗
So, where we gonna go?
说话
Out.
我是个好人 如果你认识我
See?
我是男孩
Uh...
你不是在监狱
[Antwone Sighs]
你喜欢音乐吗
I'm hungry. You?
听过他的音乐吗
I could eat.
怎样
See? That's good. You got it.
你爸去哪里
You think so? Absolutely.
他到楼下经理的厕所
I don't thinkyou have anything to worry about.
噢 是波利太太
I'm gonna giveyou my phone number.
妈
Ifyou have any problems...
这里为何这样暗
any questions at all, you can call me.
我想跟你打招呼
Any time of day or night.
你儿子这个月没交房租
Have fun. Give me a call, okay?
明天我就赶他走
We're gonna be fine.
你爱你儿子吗
Okay. You never know, son.
我不是在说房租
These things, sometimes they can escalate.
我说的是这个
Escalate into what?
我不认识你
Mywife and I went out. It escalated into marriage.
听说你很甜蜜
No, we not escalatin' into marriage.
威利 别碰她
All right, well good. You get outta here.
我要大家回去
And have fun. Hey...
你不能这样对我爸
have fun.
我要叫警察了
- Okay? - I will.
谢谢你邀请我参加舞会
Okay, see you later.
放开他 我们不要再吵
No escalating.
什么 你看过吉娃娃吗
Antwone:
没有
Okay.
我也没有
Here you go.
带他去车上
- Thankyou. - You're welcome.
我不能这样
What is this?
是 你必须做
Frappuccino.
不要
Frappuccino?
你邀请我来舞会的 是不是
Yeah. You like it?
我要昏了
For $6.00?
这是你的舞会
What doyou care how much it cost?
他的命在你手中
All the money we're makin'.
多娜 把门打开
That's why I joined the navy, you know?
有机会就打电话给我
To see the world, build a fortune.
嘿
I don't know what to do...
能听见我吗
with all the money I got.
是
Okay, now tell me...
预备好了吗
whyyou reallyjoined the navy.
你呢
For real?
是
Yeah, for real.
我数到3
All right, well...
开始 1, 2, 3
my father's a navy man, Vietnam vet...
莱纳和他朋友真厉害
and, uh, his boys were gonna grow up one day...
怎样
and join and serve just like he did.
看见吗
Only one little problem. He didn't have any boys.
就是他
- So you... - Mm-hmm.
看见他吗
So I, yep. [Chuckles]
他从旁边去
It's worth it, you know?
我不去那里
I mean, even if I hated the navy--
别怕
which I don't--
你去吧 我不去
it's worth it just to...
达达 我一直要这个
just to see his eyes and the way they shine...
中号
when I put on that uniform.
这是我们最后机会
[Chuckles]
你会喜欢这个的 宝贝
So you and him are close?
抓他
Yeah. We're close.
偷进别人的屋子
Mm.
呵呵呵...坏蛋
Can't wait to go home forThanksgiving.
我没做什么 明白我意思吗
You going home?
抓住他
I'm gonna go home.
停止 停止
Mm.
我知道你在这里
I'm kinda hungry. How aboutyou?
你抓不到我 宝贝
I could eat.
那是什么
[Laughs]
可恶 你撞了什么
What?
我不是告诉你
Nah...
若撞到东西我就开除你
Nothing.
我没撞他
What?
走吧
- What? - You sure?
快上车
- No. - Okay.
看
You shoulda ordered something.
是圣诞节老人
I like what I ordered. These are good.
转过来
You know, vegetables are good foryou.
你完了
Want to try some?
总算有房租了
Come on.
一个星期五又结束
Try it. It's good.
一个问题也解决了
It's got, uh, white cabbage...
我们把自己的东西拿回舞会
purple cabbage, yellow cabbage.
把圣诞节老人留在屋顶
I
让警察把他带走
Nasty cabbage.
迈克还是被戴蒙追着
[Laughing Together]
楼上的舞会吵的我睡不着
Man!
请你们派警察来
It's not that bad.
经理太太还是不喜欢我
Mm-hmm.
我们只是继续玩
So...
叔叔喝醉了
what doyou like to do?
爸也很会表现
Orwhat doyou want to do?
把门打开
What would you like to do?
他们想要草
I like to do?
大卫正玩的火热
Mm-hmm.
你知道我不能让多娜回到舞会
Um...
因此我给自己一个礼物
Iike, um... I want to teach.
我会回来的